ANUPAMA DILSHAN



Adelaide 5000, Australia +61 04 525 755 23 anupama.dilshan@icloud.com

Professional Summary

Software Engineer with 4+ years of full-stack experience and international experience in web application development and cloud technologies. Ready to leverage technical skills and analytical mindset to transition into digital advertising at The Quantified Web.

Skills

- Java, Python, C, C++, C#, Dart, Kotlin
- Node.js, Express.js, ASP.NET, Laravel, Flask
- · APPIAN BPMS, Salesforce, IFS ERP
- · Kubernetes, Docker, Xamarin

- HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, React, Angular, Ajax, TS
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase
- AWS, GCP, Azure, CI/CD, GitLab CI

Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Aug 2024 - Present

Department of Infrastructure and Transport - Adelaide, SA, Australia

- Developed and maintained transport regulation user management systems (TRUMPS, MySAGOV, EZYReg) using Java, AWS, and Oracle SQL, contributing to improved government service delivery.
- Implemented software solutions, including REST APIs and CI/CD pipelines, while performing system testing and ensuring data security for critical transport applications.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and optimize code for transport systems, focusing on performance improvements and streamlined functionality.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2022 - Dec 2022

Savvy finance - Norwood, SA, Australia

- Converted and optimized Apex Salesforce applications to Angular, handling increased load and complex data processing efficiently, while utilizing AngularJS and Node.js for scalable web development.
- Utilized Angular, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, and designed RESTful APIs to deliver consistent front-end applications across development, testing, and production, employing JSON for seamless server-web communication.
- Developed and maintained CI/CD pipelines using AWS DevOps, implemented Docker for consistent deployments, and utilized Zabbix for open-source monitoring to ensure application performance and reliability.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan 2020 - Mar 2023

IFS Research & Development (Pvt) Ltd Sri Lanka

- Applied SE principles in C++, C#, ASP.NET, and PL/SQL for comprehensive application development in IFS ERP, with strong Agile development experience for efficient project execution.
- Implemented best practices for application security and compliance, conducted regular audits, addressed vulnerabilities promptly, and gained experience with PostgreSQL using the command line in Linux.
- Utilized monitoring tools and practices, including open-source solutions like Zabbix, for proactive issue resolution and ensured high application reliability.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019

Devest - Mansoura, Egypt, Egypt

- Transformed Adobe XD UI designs into fully functional and mobile-responsive web applications using PHP and Laravel.
- Overcame language barriers and applied country-specific technology principles (e.g., Right-to-left) in the code.
- Worked on containerized deployments using Docker to ensure consistent environments across development and production.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

Nichelabs (Pvt) Ltd Sri Lanka

- Initiated relational & NoSQL databases and Designed APIs using Express.js, Node.js, GraphQL to allow backend tointeract smoothly with websites.
- Improved web applications using react.js, JavaScript, mobile applications using C#, .NET and styling libraries (Boostrap, Tailwind CSS) to enhance user experienceand functionality (Web & mobile friendly)
- Utilized Kubernetes Operators to manage complex application deployments and operations.

Education

Master of Science : Computer Science (GPA - 5.8/7)

Feb 2024

University of Adelaide - Adelaide, SA, Australia

 Awarded the prestigious "Global Citizens Scholarship", covering 30% of tuition fees, in recognition of outstanding academic performance in previous studies. • Key courses: Distributed systems, Mining Big Data, Applied Machine Learning, Applied Natural Language Processing, Event-Driven computing, Secure Software Engineering, Research Project.

Bachelor of Science: SoftwareEngineering

Jan 2020

Curtin University Australia

• Key courses: Operating Systems, Human Computer Interface, Distributed Computing, Programming Languages, Software Engineering Concepts, Software Engineering Testing.

Higher National Diploma(HND): SoftwareEngineering

Dec 2018

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology(SLIIT

• Key courses: Object-oriented programming, Probability & Statistics, Information Systems & Data Modeling, Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Networks, Database Management Systems

Projects

WeCare mobile app (2023)

- Developed a comprehensive smart home monitoring system aimed at preventing falls and wandering in elderly
 individuals with cognitive impairments.
- Technologies used: Dart, Pytorch, Makefile, Python, C++, CMake, Flutter, Raspberry Pi Specifics

CropSense app (2023)

- Created an AI-Generated Content (AIGC) based Leaf Disease Detection Application for agriculture.
- Technologies used: Dart, React.JS, NodeJS, Flask, Python, ChatGPT API, MongoDB

Find Love Matching application (2022)

- Developed a dating website with security methods implemented.
- Technologies used: React.JS, NodeJS, MySQL

DEVEST Tech Company Website | Egypt (2020)

- Designed and developed a dynamic, mobile-responsive website for Devest software company, including UX design, frontend and backend implementation with an admin dashboard. Added dynamic blog and portfolio sections.
- Technologies used: Laravel, PHP, HTML5, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap, MySQL,

AdobeXD Endless Runner Project (2021)

- · Developed an endless runner game prototype featuring dynamic obstacles and procedural level generation
- Technologies used: Unity3D, C#, Procedural Content Generation Algorithms

MEDIXO Medical Prescription Reader Mobile Application

- Developed a mobile application for reading handwritten medical prescriptions, assisting patients in finding nearby pharmacies and recommending drugs.
- Technologies used: Python, Kotlin, Firebase, Google vision API, Machine learning, Android SDK

DEVENT Event Management Company Website

• Technologies used: PHP, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL, Netlify

D & D Builder Fun Game

Technologies used: ASP.NET, C#, SQLite, Javascript, CSS, XML, CSS, External API

Volunteering

- Local Committee Vice President, AIESEC in University of Sri Jayewardenepura: Spearheaded team operations and strategic planning, enhancing organizational impact and fostering leadership development within the committee.
- *Team Leader, Project "Be Sri Lanka"*: Led a diverse volunteer team in promoting sustainable tourism and cultural preservation, coordinating with multiple stakeholders and managing project execution.
- *Marketing Head, International Congress*: Strategized and executed comprehensive marketing campaigns, significantly boosting event visibility and engagement across various digital and traditional platforms.

accomplishments

- 9th country rank, 3rd state rank for GCE Advanced Levels examination (2016)
- Best Emerging Young Leader (2019) AIESEC in Sri Lanka
- Best Leadership entity in Outgoing Global Talent (2021) AIESEC in Sri Lanka
- Excellence in Outgoing Global Talent (2021) Asia Pacific Region
- Best young Leader | Most outstanding project (2019) AIESEC in University of Sri Jayewardenepura
- Excellence performance in Engineering Technology (2016) Bandaranayake college

References

- Michael Baum [Team Leader] Department of Infrastructure and Transport Contact: michael.baum@sa.gov.au
- **Dr. Yongliang Qiao** [Research Fellow] Australian Institute for Machine Learning, University of Adelaide Contact: yongliang.qiao@adelaide.edu.au
- Bill Tsouvalas [Managing Director] Savvy Finance, Adelaide, Australia Contact: billt@savvy.com.au